Inventory of the International Military Tribunal for the Far East records 49016.4087879
Hoover Institution Archives
International Military Tribunal for the Far East records
1920-1948
1889-1948
Hoover Institution Archives
International Military Tribunal for the Far East
49016.4087879
81.5 linear feet 115 manuscript boxes, 1 envelope, 242 volumes.
Court exhibits, transcripts, summaries of proceedings, summations of counsel, judgments, photographs, and indices relating to the trial of Japanese military and government officials accused of war crimes during the Second World War.
Volume 1-242 / shelf 255
Box 1-115
Shelf 12.36/39
Access
The collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least two business days in advance of intended use.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1949.
Related Collection
International Military Tribunal proceedings, Hoover Institution Archives
Historical Note
The International Military Tribunal for the Far East (IMTFE), also known as the Tokyo War Crimes Tribunal or the Tokyo Trials, lasted from April 29, 1946 to November 12, 1948. Established by special proclamation of the Supreme Commander for the Allied Powers (SCAP), U.S. General Douglas MacArthur, the IMTFE sought to try Japanese government officials and military leaders for the incitement and perpetration of World War II and war crimes throughout the conflict.
For more than two years, eleven judges representing the Allied signatories of the Instrument of Surrender, as well as India and the Philippines, heard cases against twenty-eight defendants, including General Hideki Tojo. From November 4 to 12, 1948, the tribunal rendered judgments against twenty-five defendants (two defendants died during the trial and one was deemed incompetent to stand trial). Seven defendants were sentenced to death, sixteen to life imprisonment, one to twenty years' imprisonment, and one to seven years' imprisonment.
Similar to its German counterpart in Nuremberg, the trial's charges, evidence, defense, and rulings mark the IMTFE as an important moment in the reshaping of modern international law in the post-World War II period.
Scope and Content Note
Exhibits, evidence, transcripts, indices of the record, and other documents relating to the trial of Japanese officials and military leaders accused of war crimes during the Second World War. Documents reflect significant contributions to international law within the contexts of crimes against humanity, wars of aggression, and other relevant subjects.
List of Indices in the Hoover Archives Reading Room
1. Dull and Umemura. The Tokyo Trials: A Functional Index (1957). 94 p.
2. Index of Rejected Prosecution Documents (undated). 17 p. (2 copies)
3. Index of Rejected Defense Documents (undated). 44 p.
4. Index of (defense) witnesses, 28 February 1947 - 10 February 1948 (undated). 117 p.
5. Index of (prosecution) witnesses, 17 June - 16 August 1946; 28 August - 29 November 1946 (undated). 13 p. (2 copies)
6. Index of motions, arguments, decisions, objections in open court (undated). 36 p.
7. Supreme Command for the Allied Powers. International Prosecution Section (IPS). Revised index to documents by defendants (at the Tokyo War Crime Trials). Also, numerical list of IPS documents introduced as court exhibits (1947). 55 p. and 32 p.
8. General Index of the Record of the Prosecution's Case (1947). 101 p.
9. General Index of the Record of the Defense Case (1947). 152 p.
10. Maxon, Yale Candee. Index to documents (by phase and subject) (1947). 20 p.
11. Maxon, Yale Candee. Index to documents not specifically linked to one or more of the defendants (1947). 17 p.
12. Index of Exhibits (undated). 592 p.
Arrangement Statement
The collection, consisting of both loose documents and bound volumes, is arranged alphabetically by subject. To request bound volumes, please note the title of the volume and the volume number, if applicable.
Exhibits, Rejected Defense Documents, and Rejected Prosecution Documents contain corresponding indices that can be used to identify the documents found in these series. A link to a PDF version of each corresponding index can be found in a scope and content note at the beginning of these series.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Japan--History, Military.; Japan--History--20th century.; Japan--History--Allied occupation, 1945-1952.; Japan--History.; Japan--Politics and government--20th century.; Japan.; Tokyo Trial, Tokyo, Japan, 1946-1948.; War crime trials--Japan.; World War, 1939-1945--Japan.; World War, 1939-1945.; International Military Tribunal for the Far East
- Analyses of Documentary Evidence, 1946-1948 (Volume on shelf)
  Scope and Contents note
  Comprised of 15 bound volumes containing analyses and descriptions of documents presented by both counsels. Volume 1 includes a summary of the entire set of volumes as well as an explanation for missing document ranges. Not all documents included in this series were accepted by the court and presented during the trial. For items that were accepted as evidence, see the Exhibits series.
  - Documents 1-499, 1946, 1948 January 15 (Volume 1)
  - Documents 500-730, 1946 (Volume 2)
  - Documents 731-949, 1946 (Volume 3)
  - Documents 950-1149, 1946 (Volume 4)
  - Documents 1150-1375, 1946 (Volume 5)
  - Documents 1376-1575, 1946 (Volume 6)
  - Documents 1576-1829, 1946 (Volume 7)
  - Documents 1830-2194, 1946 (Volume 8)
  - Documents 2195-2475, 1946 (Volume 9)
  - Documents 2476-2701, 1946 (Volume 10)
  - Documents 2702-3004, 1946-1947 (Volume 11)
  - Documents 3005-3318, 1947 (Volume 12)
  - Documents 3500-3517, 1947 (Volume 13)
  - Documents 4001-4059, 1946 (Volume 14)
  - Documents 4060-4097, 1946-1948 (Volume 15)
- Decisions of Conferences, 1947 June 16 (Volume on shelf)
  Comprised of one bound volume containing a report by assistant prosecutor Joseph F. English titled "Decisions of Imperial Conferences, Liaison Conferences, Privy Council Meetings, Cabinet Meetings, Four Ministers' Conferences, Five Ministers' Conferences, Senior Statesmen's Meetings, Supreme War Plans Council, Joint Conferences and Miscellaneous Conferences, as Found in the Prosecution's Evidence." The report is a chronological account of various meetings between Japanese government and military officials. The first section of the report is an index organized by name and lists all meetings attended by each individual. The second section of the report describes the meetings themselves, as well as resolutions and policies discussed during the meetings.
- Defense Documents, undated
  Contains various documents presented by the defense. Includes complete opening statements on behalf of each defendant and for the defense team as a whole.
  - "Comparative Study on Wang-Tao and Pa-Tao" (Defense Doc 3054), undated (Box-folder 114: 5)
  - Defense opening statements, undated (Box-folder 114: 6)
    Contains opening statements from the defense council framing responses to arguments introduced by the prosecution, including Japanese aggression in various geographic regions.
  - Defense opening statements, by defendant name, undated (Box-folder 115: 1, Box-folder 114: 7)
    Contains opening statements on behalf of each defendant except Matsui Iwane and Oka Takazumi.
  - Defense summation on personal responsibility (Defense Doc. 3037), undated (Box-folder 115: 2)
- Exhibits, 1889-1947
  Contains telegrams, diaries, books, excerpts, maps, treaties, photographs, and other documents presented as evidence by both councils. Exhibits 1-2282 are documents from the prosecution; exhibits 2283-3915 are documents from the defense.
  The exhibits are arranged numerically. See index for document titles. Missing exhibits are noted with either circles on the left-hand margin of the Index or in a scope and contents note at the appropriate box level of this guide.
  Index
  Downloadable Index of Exhibits
  - Exhibits 1-22, 1899-1947, undated (Box 1)
  - Exhibits 23-52, 1919-1943 (Box 2)
  - Exhibits 53-63, 1932-1938, undated (Box 3)
  - Exhibits 64-100, 1889, 1933-1947, undated (Box 4)
  - Exhibits 102-129, 1946-1947 (Box 5)
  - Exhibits 130-163, 1897, 1931-1947, undated (Box 6)
  - Exhibits 164-193, 1927-1947, undated (Box 7)
  - Exhibits 194-236, 1932-1937 (Box 8)
  - Exhibits 237-271, 1932-1947, undated (Box 9)
  - Exhibits 272-314, 1931, 1939, 1947, undated (Box 10)
  - Exhibits 315-370, 1938-1947, undated (Box 11)
  - Exhibits 371-415, 1934-1947, undated (Box 12)
  - Exhibits 416-446, 1934-1947 (Box 13)
  - Exhibits 447-473, 1938-1947 (Box 14)
  - Exhibits 474-497, 1937-1939, 1947, undated (Box 15)
  - Exhibits 498-548, 1939-1940 (Box 16)
    Missing Exhibit 540.
  - Exhibits 549-592, 1938-1941 (Box 17)
  - Exhibits 593-630, 1932-1947 (Box 18)
  - Exhibits 631-674, 1931, 1937, 1940-1947 (Box 19)
  - Exhibits 675-710, 1931-1945, undated (Box 20)
  - Exhibits 711-743, 1931-1947 (Box 21)
    Missing Exhibit 722.
  - Exhibits 744-793, 1931-1947 (Box 22)
  - Exhibits 794-838, 1941-1947 (Box 23)
  - Exhibits 839-857, 1925-1941 (Box 24)
    Missing Exhibits 843-848, 858.
  - Exhibits 859-881, 1931-1942 (Box 25)
  - Exhibits 882-942, 1931-1947, undated (Box 26)
  - Exhibits 943-1021, 1936-1941 (Box 27)
  - Exhibits 1022-1076, 1938-1941 (Box 28)
  - Exhibits 1077-1139, 1941, 1946 (Box 29)
  - Exhibits 1140-1209, 1940-1941, 1947 (Box 30)
  - Exhibits 1210-1251, 1931-1941, 1947, undated (Box 31)
    Missing Exhibit 1245-B, contains unlisted Exhibits 1245-L, 1245-M.
  - Exhibits 1252-1274, 1941-1945, undated (Box 32)
  - Exhibits 1275-1326, 1938-1945 (Box 33)
  - Exhibits 1327-1374, 1935-1945 (Box 34)
  - Exhibits 1375-1493, 1942-1945 (Box 35)
  - Exhibits 1494-1564, 1942, 1947, undated (Box 36)
  - Exhibits 1565-1632, 1945-1946 (Box 37)
  - Exhibits 1633-1686, 1942-1946 (Box 38)
  - Exhibits 1687-1744, 1944-1946 (Box 39)
  - Exhibits 1745-1792, 1946, undated (Box 40)
  - Exhibits 1793-1840, 1945-1946, undated (Box 41)
  - Exhibits 1841-1909, 1944-1946 (Box 42)
  - Exhibits 1910-1965, 1942-1946 (Box 43)
  - Exhibits 1966-2016, 1942-1946, undated (Box 44)
  - Exhibits 2017-2055, 1939-1945, undated (Box 45)
  - Exhibits 2056-2112, 1942-1946 (Box 46)
  - Exhibits 2113-2174, 1942-1946 (Box 47)
  - Exhibits 2175-2209, 1925-1943, undated (Box 48)
  - Exhibits 2210-2250, 1936-1946 (Box 49)
    Missing Exhibit 2243.
  - Exhibits 2251-2315, 1895-1925, 1932-1940 (Box 50)
  - Exhibits 2317-2344, 1915-1922, 1939-1947 (Box 51)
  - Exhibits 2347-2398, 1889-1946 (Box 52)
  - Exhibits 2399-2437, 1931-1937, 1946, undated (Box 53)
  - Exhibits 2438-2472, 1912, 1930-1943, undated (Box 54)
  - Exhibits 2473-2506, 1913, 1934-1937, undated (Box 55)
  - Exhibits 2507-2547, 1928-1939, 1946 (Box 56)
  - Exhibits 2548-2592, 1938-1939, 1944-1946, undated (Box 57)
  - Exhibits 2593-2647, 1860, 1936-1942 (Box 58)
  - Exhibits 2649-2694, 1931-1947 (Box 59)
  - Exhibits 2695-2729, 1911, 1926, 1933-1941, undated (Box 60)
  - Exhibits 2730-2771C, 1938-1946 (Box 61)
  - Exhibits 2772A-2832, 1931-1941 (Box 62)
  - Exhibits 2833-2907, 1931-1941, 1946, undated (Box 63)
  - Exhibits 2908-2975A, 1941, 1945-1946 (Box 64)
  - Exhibits 2976-3011, 1923, 1940-1946 (Box 65)
  - Exhibits 3012A-3057, 1903, 1931-1946, undated (Box 66)
  - Exhibits 3058-3103, 1941-1947, undated (Box 67)
  - Exhibits 3104-3145, 1942-1945, undated (Box 68)
  - Exhibits 3146-3189, 1932-1937, 1946, undated (Box 69)
    Missing Exhibit 3160.
  - Exhibits 3190-3241, 1893, 1929-1938, 1943-1946 (Box 70)
  - Exhibits 3242-3301, 1934-1938, 1941 (Box 71)
  - Exhibits 3302-3339A, 1939-1946 (Box 72)
  - Exhibits 3340-3346, 1938, 1946 (Box 73)
  - Exhibits 3347-3391, 1898, 1931-1946, undated (Box 74)
  - Exhibits 3392-3439, 1931-1947 (Box 75)
    Missing Exhibit 3440.
  - Exhibits 3441-3479, 1927, 1931-1942, undated (Box 76)
  - Exhibits 3480-3529, 1892, 1935-1947 (Box 77)
  - Exhibits 3530-3575, 1931-1947 (Box 78)
  - Exhibits 3576-3609A, 1898, 1933-1939, undated (Box 79)
  - Exhibits 3610-3651, 1932-1941, 1947 (Box 80)
  - Exhibits 3652-3665, 1939-1942, undated (Box 81)
  - Exhibits 3666-3709, 1919-1947 (Box 82)
  - Exhibits 3710-3714 (A28), undated (Box 83)
  - Exhibits 3714 (A29)-3748, 1931-1942 (Box 84)
  - Exhibits 3749-3839, 1919-1920, 1937-1946 (Box 85)
  - Exhibits 3840-3893, 1933-1948, undated (Box 86)
  - Exhibits 3894-3915, 1943-1945, undated (Box 87)
- Judgments, Opinions, and Verdicts, 1948, undated
  Includes official judgement of the tribunal, as well as individual and dissenting opinions from the justices.
  - Judgments, 1948 November 4-12 (Volume on shelf)
    Comprised of six bound volumes. Contains the full text and transcript of the tribunal judgment, organized chronologically.
  - Annexes, 1948 November (Volume on shelf)
    Comprised of one bound volume. Annex of documents and treaties cited directly or indirectly in the tribunal judgment.
  - Judgment of Henri Bernald [Bernard], 1948 November 12 (Volume on shelf)
    Comprised of one bound volume. Dissenting opinion from Judge Henri Bernard, the French representative to the bench.
  - Judgment of Justice Pal, undated (Volume on shelf)
    Comprised of three bound volumes. Dissenting opinion from Radhabinod Pal, the Indian representative to the bench.
  - Opinion of Justice Jaranilla, 1948 November 1 (Volume on shelf)
    Scope and Contents notes
    Comprised of one bound volume. Dissenting opinion from Delfin Jaranilla, the Filipino representative to the bench.
  - Opinion of Justice Röling, 1948 November 12 (Volume on shelf)
    Comprised of one bound volume. Dissenting opinion from Bert Röling, the Dutch representative to the bench.
  - Separate Opinion of the President, 1948 November 1 (Volume on shelf)
    Comprised of one bound volume. Dissenting opinion from William Webb, the Tribunal President and Australian representative to the bench.
  - "Summary of the Final Judgment. International Military Tribunal for the Far East. Press Release. Summary No. 1,", undated (Box-folder 115: 5)
  - "Verdict Pronounced by the International Military Tribunal for the Far East on the 25 Japanese War Crimes Suspects on Nov 12, 1948 (Excerpt),", 1948 November 12 (Box-folder 115: 6)
- Narrative Summary of the Records, 1946 June 14 - 1948 February 10 (Volume on shelf)
  Comprised of 16 bound volumes organized by date. Contains a full summary of the trial proceedings, with an emphasis on the introduction of exhibits, witness testimonies, and cross-examinations. Events or documents referenced in this summary include a parenthetical citation noting their location in the full trial record (Proceedings).
  - 1946
    - June 14-August 5 (Volume 1)
    - August 5-September 13 (Volume 2)
    - September 13-October 21 (Volume 3)
    - October 21-November 13 (Volume 4)
    - November 13-December 12 (Volume 5)
    - December 12-1947 January 15 (Volume 6)
  - 1947
    - January 15-March 18 (Volume 7)
    - March 18-April 22 (Volume 8)
    - April 22-May 22 (Volume 9)
    - May 22-August 14 (Volume 10)
    - August 14-September 10 (Volume 11)
    - September 10-October 6 (Volume 12)
    - October 6-29 (Volume 13)
    - October 29-November 19 (Volume 14)
    - November 19-December 17 (Volume 15)
    - December 17-1948 February 10 (Volume 16)
- Proceedings, 1946-1948, undated
  Contains the full transcript and record of the trial proceedings. An abridged descriptive summary, with significant trial events such as documents introduced and motions made, can be found in the Narrative Summary of the Records. Documents in this series include cross-references to documents located in the Narrative Summary of the Records.
  - Proceedings and pleadings, 1946-1948, undated (Box-folder 87: 11-12, Box 88)
    Includes a docket and chronology.
  - Proceedings in chambers, 1946 May 4 - 1948 April 30 (Box-folder 90: 1-3, Box 89)
  - Proceedings in conference room, 1946 July 1-16 (Box-folder 90: 4)
  - Proceedings in courtroom, 1946 April 22 - 1948 November 12 (Volume on shelf)
    Comprised of 166 bound volumes organized by date. To request materials, indicate the date or dates you would like to see, and the corresponding volumes will be retrieved. Please note, gaps exist in the date range which represent days that the tribunal did not meet.
  - Unnumbered proceedings and pleadings, undated (Box-folder 90: 5)
- Prosecution Documents, 1938, 1946, 1947
  Contains various documents presented by the prosecution.
  - Prosecution documents 1685C, 2075, 2152, 1938, 1946 (Box-folder 116: 3)
  - Psychiatric examination of Okawa, Shumei, 1947 January 30, March 13 (Box-folder 116: 4)
- Rejected Defense Documents, 1896-1947, undated
  Documents are arranged numerically. See index for document titles.
  Downloadable Index of Rejected Defense Documents
  - Documents 54-70, 1935-1941, undated (Box-folder 90: 6-11)
  - Documents 77-199, 1905, 1924-1943, undated (Box 91)
  - Documents 202-262, 1898-1919, 1926-1945, undated (Box 92)
  - Documents 267-426, 1896-1947, undated (Box 93)
  - Documents 428-626, 1924-1947 (Box 94)
  - Documents 629-919, 1925-1947, undated (Box 95)
  - Documents 953-1035, 1931-1947, undated (Box 96)
  - Documents 1066-1213, 1932-1947, undated (Box 97)
  - Documents 1223-1444, 1901, 1937-1945, undated (Box 98)
  - Documents 1447-1660, 1935-1947, undated (Box 99)
  - Documents 1664-1885, 1920-1946, undated (Box 100)
  - Documents 1895-1961, 1929-1947, undated (Box 101)
  - Documents 1964-2251, 1921-1946, undated (Box 102)
  - Documents 2253-2525, 1931-1946, undated (Box 103)
  - Documents 2528-2871, 1931-1947, undated (Box 104)
  - Documents 2876-3088, 1932-1948, undated (Box-folder 105: 1-27)
  - Duplicate rejected defense documents, 1898-1947, undated (Box-folder 114: 1-4, Boxes 112-113, Box-folder 111: 11-12)
- Rejected Prosecution Documents, 1904-1947
  Documents arranged numerically. See index for document titles.
  Downloadable Index of Rejected Prosecution Documents
  - Documents 15-465, 1933-1941, undated (Box-folder 105: 28-37)
  - Documents 472-1204F, 1926-1945, undated (Box 106)
  - Documents 1217-1634, 1928-1946, undated (Box 107)
  - Documents 1676-2534, 1931-1946, undated (Box 108)
  - Documents 2542-3332, 1904, 1921-1947, undated (Box 109)
  - Documents 3334-6910, 1934-1946, undated (Box 110)
  - Documents 6911-9563, 1941-1946, undated (Box-folder 111: 1-10)
- Summation for the Defense, circa 1948 (Volume on shelf)
  Contains the final review of the defense. Comprised of 24 bound volumes, organized by subject.
  - Volume 1
    Analyses of the trial within the scope of international law. Contains defense documents 3054, 2987, 3098, 3097 and 3094.
  - Volume 2
    Discusses Japanese foreign relations with Manchuria, China, Russia, Germany, and Italy. Contains defense documents 3071, 3034, 3099, and 3104.
  - Volume 3
    Summarizes the defense's case regarding Japanese military aggression. The bulk of this volume is comprised of a section titled "Japan Was Provoked into a War of Self-Defense." Contains defense documents 3095, 3100, 3102, and 3093.
  - Summations of defendants, circa 1948
    Comprised of 19 bound volumes, organized by defendant's last name. Some volumes contain summations for multiple defendants.
    - Araki, Sadao
    - Dohihara [Doihara], Kenji
    - Hashimoto, Kingorō
    - Hata, Shunroku
    - Hiranuma, Kiichirō and Hoshino, Naoki
    - Hirota, Kōki
    - Itagaki, Seishirō
    - Kaya, Okinori
    - Kido, Kōichi
    - Kimura, Heitaro and Koiso, Kuniaki
    - Mutō, Akira and Minami, Jirō
    - Ōshima, Hiroshi
    - Satō, Kenryō; Matsui, Iwane; and Oka, Takazumi
    - Shigemitsu, Mamoru and Shimada, Shigetarō
    - Shiratori, Toshio
    - Suzuki, Teiichi and Umezu, Yoshijirō
    - Tōgō, Shigenori, 2 volumes
    - Tōjō, Hideki
  - POW [Prisoner of War] Summation, circa 1948
    Comprised of one bound volume. Contains the defense's response to the prosecution's charges of Japanese military aggression and mistreatment of POWs. Includes excerpts from and references to witness testimonies.
  - Reply of Prosecution to Defense Summation, circa 1948
    Comprised of one bound volume divided into three sections: the USSR, China, and other topics, including the defense team's case regarding provocation and self-defense within the context of international law.
- Summation of the Prosecution, circa 1948 (Volume on shelf)
  Comprised of six bound volumes. Contains sections titled "Japanese Aggression in Manchuria, Russia and against the Western Powers" and "Crimes Against Peace," as well as summaries of the prosecution's case against each defendant. Volume 1 includes a table of contents.
- Photographs, 1945 October (Box-folder 115: 7)
  Contains four prints depicting activities of the IMTFE in Japan, including photos of the trial and seated defendants.
- Miscellaneous, undated (Box-folder 115: 8)
  Contains a number of unidentifiable loose documents, including possible excerpts from judges' opinions.